Craig Wellspring

Software Developer and Game Designer

ABOUT ME

I've been interested in computer programming since I discovered game modding as a young teenager and have continued to practice my coding skills in my spare time until today. I've worked in a diverse set of environments which has given me a broad and balanced perspective and an affirmation that software development is my real passion.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School - July 2021 - June 2022

An intensive one-year program teaching the skills and technologies necessary to become a full-stack software developer in today's tech environment.

- Git & Github version control
- Remote project collaboration, simulated agile work environment
- ERDs, dependency charts, wireframe design
- Developing applications using popular tech stacks that include React, ASP.Net, and SQL

PROJECTS

Housekeeper – NSS Front-End Capstone Project

An application which allows users to share a collection of to-do lists meant to ease the communication between housemates.

https://house-keeper.netlify.app

Developed using React.js and Supabase.

Minibar Tender - NSS Full-Stack Capstone Project

A Point-Of-Sale and inventory tracking application for two person minibar operations.

https://minibartender.netlify.app

Developed using React.js, C#, .Net, and Supabase.

Portfolio Site - Personal Project

My personal site is designed as a portfolio for all of my work, a small profile of my life, a showcase of what I am capable of, and a playground for things I want to try in web development.

https://craig-wellspring.netlify.app

Developed using Three.js, React.js and Firebase.

CONTACT

(636) 359-9246
wellspring.craig@gmail.com
craig-wellspring.netlify.app
github.com/craig-wellspring

linkedin.com/in/craigwellspring

SKILLS

Full-stack web application development

UI/UX Design

3D and Game Design

Database Implementations

Management and Organization

Problem Solving

LANGUAGES

English

C#, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Bootcamp Certificate
Massage Therapy License

Iiu-Iitsu Blue Belt

Bartending Certification

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

July 2021 - June 2022

Nashville School of Massage Therapy

August 2016 - February 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Summary:

- 10+ years in the restaurant industry, 2 years in massage therapy, 1 year in production rigging, 2 years in appliance repair
- Experience in varied high and low stress environments, adept at learning on the job, problem solving, organization, managing teams, and technical communication with customers, teammates and management.

Recent Employment History:

Barback, Honky Tonk Central Nashville, TN

3/2021 - Current

- Stocking and rotating alcohol inventory
- Assisting bartenders and maintaining the bar area
- Minor security duties

Service Technician, National Laundry Equipment Nashville, TN

7/2019 — 3/2021

- Installing, maintaining, and uninstalling commercial and industrial laundry equipment
- Duties included operating heavy vehicles and equipment, plumbing, electrical, metalwork, cement
 masonry, carpentry, technical troubleshooting, computer programming, money handling, vehicle
 maintenance and team coordination.

Stagehand, Convention Productions Rigging Nashville, TN

2/2019 — 3/2020

- Unloading, setting up, breaking down, and re-loading Audio, Lighting, Video, Automation, Pyrotechnic and Staging equipment for large scale convention and music productions
- Following complex instructions and working safely and seamlessly with a large team

Line Cook, Fenwick's 300 Nashville, TN

9/2018 — 7/2019

• Preparing food, cleaning equipment, maintaining a clean working environment and managing inventories

Chiropractic Therapy Assistant, Nashville Spine and Sport Nashville, TN

5/2018 —10/2018

- Performing massage therapy and related chiropractic therapies
- Taking notes and maintaining accurate patient records
- Booking and performing massage therapy appointments with office clients